<page parent="instruments">
    <title>Instruments - Guitars</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            I own some guitars and guitar-like instruments.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sidebar heading="Other Instruments">
        <sections>
            <section id="Lisa">
                <values>
                    <make>Martin</make>
                    <model>?</model>
                    <cost>$1000</cost>
                    <year>circa 2010</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This guitar is so light, but it has a vibrant sound. She's a cutaway
                            acoustic-electric with built-in tuner and 2-band EQ.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Pinkie">
                <values>
                    <make>Custom</make>
                    <model>Stratocaster copy</model>
                    <pickups>3 single-coil Lace Sensor Gold</pickups>
                    <cost>~$300</cost>
                    <year>N/A</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            I bought this guitar off the side of the road. A woman was selling it; her son had owned and
                            played it but had moved out or whatever and it wasn't being used. I came over, tried it out,
                            and took it home.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Originally this guitar was a Stratocaster copy made by Kramer. The body and headstock were
                            entirely covered in tiger fur. That's right, tiger fur. I don't know whether that's the way it
                            came or whether that was a custom job. The paint underneath was black. At any rate, I stripped
                            off the shag and painted the body a nice pink color. I still have to go back and lacquer this
                            paint job...someday.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            I replaced all of the electronics with a standard Stratocaster setup from the 90s, with Lace Sensor
                            Gold pickups and Ernie Ball trim pots (I think). All I need is a new neck and it will be a pretty
                            decent custom Strat copy.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Uke">
                <values>
                    <make>Cordoba</make>
                    <model>20TM-CE</model>
                    <tuning>G4 C4 E4 A4</tuning>
                    <cost>$200</cost>
                    <year>2011</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This ukulele is fun to play. Not only does it have a cutaway, but it is also
                            acoustic-electric, with a GREAT amplified sound.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Rogue">
                <values>
                    <make>Rogue</make>
                    <model>RA-100</model>
                    <cost>$100 (gift)</cost>
                    <year>2007</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            I got this guitar for my birthday many years back. It was the first guitar I could
                            call my own. It has a great sound, but miserable action--the strings are too high
                            and no neck adjustment is possible.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <hidden reason="gave to Bill">
            <section id="Derp">
                <values>
                    <make>Yamaha</make>
                    <model>FD01</model>
                    <tuning>open D</tuning>
                    <cost>free</cost>
                    <year>circa 2000s</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            My buddy was throwing this guitar out. I didn't figure out why it was so worthless until I got
                            it home. The strings are a bitch to change because the bridge and pins are so cheap. The
                            entire neck is twisted or warped in such a way that the strings touch the fretboard when
                            they're depressed (which results in buzzing). I decided to open-tune this guitar and keep
                            it around for experimenting with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slide_guitar">slide</a>
                            technique.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            </hidden>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>