<page parent="instruments">
    <title>Instruments - Trombones</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            I own a few trombones. I've bought and sold over a dozen horns since 2001.
        </p>
        <p>
            While playing tenor, I am exclusively using Vincent Bach 6 1/2 AL mouthpieces, specifically, the vintage when the "1/2" was stamped
            <a prefix=" " href="/gallery/heap/6.5al0.jpg">like this</a>, which was before they started stamping it <a prefix=" " href="/gallery/heap/6.5al1.jpg">like this</a>.
            I am not sure exactly what changed about the 6 1/2 AL over its history, I just wanted to be consistent when I bought multiple copies.
        </p>
        <p>
            I now exclusively use a <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.monette.net/newsite/index.htm">Monette</a>
            BT-2 for bass trombone. I tried using my Bach one day after using the Monette for a long time and found it to be too stuffy--there is no comparison. The Monette is so open. 
        </p>
    </header>
    <sidebar heading="Other Instruments">
        <sections>
            <section id="Cherie">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn</make>
                    <model>18H (bell); 14H (slide)</model>
                    <bore>.484"</bore>
                    <bell>7 1/2", lacquered copper</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>~$250</cost>
                    <year>circa 1966 (bell)</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This is my baby, my favorite trombone. I have owned the bell section for several years. For a long time I was
                            using a slide that my father built out of two other Conn slides (one a 14H, the other a 48H). The stockings and
                            inner tubes on that slide were pitted and rough, but the action was still smooth for a long time. I played it to
                            the point where the slide was no longer usable. To get a replacement slide I bought a used Conn 14H on eBay. So
                            Cherie is actually two trombones.  I recently worked on the slide a little and brought it from an 8 to a 9.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Cherie gets her name from her bell, which is made from copper. Typical brass bells are an alloy made from roughly 70% copper
                            and 30% zinc. Cherie's bell is 100% copper. Copper bells, accoring to <a prefix=" " href="http://cderksen.home.xs4all.nl/ConnArticle20.html">Conn</a>,
                            produce a darker sound with increased directional projection. While I have found that to be true, I cherish
                            Cherie more for her unique "cherry" appearance.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/cherie.jpg</src>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Maura">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn</make>
                    <model>18H</model>
                    <bore>.484"</bore>
                    <bell>7", unlacquered copper</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>~$150</cost>
                    <year>circa 1957</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This horn is very similar to <a prefix=" " href="#Cherie">Cherie</a>, but the bell is slightly smaller, and it has no lacquer.
                            The result is a noticably darker sound. The bell section is also a slightly different dimension (1/4" <i space-after="false">longer</i>), which
                            means all of the slide positions look different; I have to close my eyes to play in tune.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/maura.jpg</src>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Charlotte">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn</make>
                    <model>6H</model>
                    <bore>.500"</bore>
                    <bell>8", silver</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>~$650</cost>
                    <year>circa 1970</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This is my silver concert horn. I bought Charlotte on eBay while I was in high school, right around the time I decided to
                            sell my Bach 42BO. I don't like to take her out of the case because she is in such nice condition. She does
                            have a few small dents, and some weird mark on the silver just below the tuning slide, but she's still beautiful from end
                            to end. The slide is almost perfect.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/charlotte.jpg</src>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Cleveland">
                <values>
                    <make>Cleveland</make>
                    <model>Superior</model>
                    <bore></bore>
                    <bell>7 3/8", lacquered yellow brass</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>7/10</slide>
                    <cost>Free!</cost>
                    <year>circa 1965</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This horn came "free" with a Conn 4H that I bought on eBay (the auction was for two bones, but I wanted the 4H). I ended
                            up keeping this one because of its impeccable condition and resold the 4H for the same price as I paid for both originally
                            (thereby making Cleveland a free horn). The condition has worsened greatly since. The slide
                            has been dented and fixed several times. I was dancing on stage one night; I jumped too high and fell into Steve's drum set, and
                            squished part of the bell section on a piece of hardware. Oops. Still plays great! I usually march with this horn. When
                            <l href="#Cherie">Cherie</l> was out of service, I played this horn a <i space-after="false">lot</i>.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Maureen">
                <values>
                    <make>King</make>
                    <model>4B Sonorous</model>
                    <bore>.547"</bore>
                    <bell>8 1/2", lacquered yellow brass</bell>
                    <key>Bb/F</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>~$425</cost>
                    <year>circa 1978</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            I bought this horn on eBay because I needed a Bb/F trombone for use with the Cape Ann Big Band. I wanted to play 4th trombone,
                            which is impossible on a straight tenor. When I first played this horn, the slide was stuck, so I could only play in 1st position, but
                            it didn't matter. I was immediately amazed by the sound produced. The horn is aptly named "Sonorous".
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Darcie">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn</make>
                    <model>60H, custom</model>
                    <bore>.562"</bore>
                    <bell>9 1/2", lacquered red brass</bell>
                    <key>Bb/F/D</key>
                    <slide>10/10</slide>
                    <cost>$2600</cost>
                    <year>circa 1972</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This is my new love, my first triple horn. I love old Conns so I bought this one without having tried it.
                            I am very pleased with my decision, as this horn plays great. The tuning slide on this horn is built into the handslide,
                            so that the entire bell section can be conical (a tuning slide in the bell requires two cylindrical sections in the bell).
                            The sound is big and dark.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            This horn was customized by the previous owner. It was originally a single-valve 60H, and a second Conn valve was added
                            to make the horn more like a 62H. The valve linkages were replaced with ball linkages which are incredibly smooth and quiet.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/darcie.jpg</src>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Lily">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn</make>
                    <model>16A</model>
                    <bore>??</bore>
                    <bell>4", silver</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>7/10</slide>
                    <cost>$1000</cost>
                    <year>circa 1921</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            Never in my life did I expect to own one of these. This item has extremely high levels of both rareness and coolness.
                            You might call her a soprano trombone, or perhaps a slide cornet. I just call her Lily. At over 90 years old, she's the
                            oldest working instrument I own.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Lily, like <l space-after="false" href="#Darcie">Darcie</l>, has her tuning slide built into the handslide. This allows the bell to be conical,
                            which is traditionally the mark of a cornet versus a trumpet (which would be more cylindrical). Her finish is an
                            old-style silver which is unpolished with a matte appearance. The inside of the bell has a gold wash which is in almost
                            perfect condition.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Lily is <i space-after="false">tiny</i>. I really didn't expect her to be so small.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/lily.jpg</src>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <hidden id="Frankenstein">
                <values>
                    <make>Conn, Yamaha, ???</make>
                    <model>Mix</model>
                    <bore>.532"</bore>
                    <bell>9", lacquered yellow brass</bell>
                    <key>Bb/F/Gb/D</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>
                        <em>On loan</em>
                    </cost>
                    <year>
                        <em>unknown</em>
                    </year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            I am currently borrowing this horn from a fellow <l href="/pages/timski/bands.html#Boston Fireman's Band">BFB</l> boner.
                            It was the first quadruple horn I had ever handled. This
                            horn was most definitely constructed out of three separate horns. The bell is from an Elkhart Conn
                            bass trombone (possibly a 73H). The slide is from a Yamaha tenor. I still haven't been able to identify the valve set.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </hidden>
            <section id="Holton Collegiate">
                <values>
                    <make>Holton</make>
                    <model>Collegiate</model>
                    <bore>.484"</bore>
                    <bell>7 1/2", lacquered yellow brass</bell>
                    <key>Eb</key>
                    <slide>8/10</slide>
                    <cost>
                        30 books of <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%26H_Green_Stamps">green stamps</a>
                    </cost>
                    <year>circa 1966</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This was the first trombone I ever played. It was my father's horn when he was a student. It was my only horn for
                            several years. It became secondary to my Conn Director when I received the latter sometime around 2001.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Selman Eb Alto">
                <values>
                    <make>Selman</make>
                    <model>Alto Trombone</model>
                    <bore>.476"</bore>
                    <bell>6 1/2", silver</bell>
                    <key>Eb</key>
                    <slide>9/10</slide>
                    <cost>$230</cost>
                    <year>2005</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            I bought this horn out of sheer curiosity. I had been dying to get my hands on an alto trombone, but
                            most models were for professionals and had huge price tags. I saw this horn and couldn't resist. Its
                            made by "Selman"--a knock off of "Selmer"--which is most likely an overseas manufacturer. All in all this horn
                            is junk, along with all the other knock-off overseas brands like "Durand" and "Mendid". The silver
                            plating is full of pits. The tuning is not quite Eb--to get to Eb you have to have the tuning slide
                            all the way out, and even then the intonation across the horn is terrible. It plays like it has a hole in it, as if
                            the water key were being held open. Bottom line: you get what you pay for.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="pBone">
                <values>
                    <make>Jiggs</make>
                    <model>pBone</model>
                    <bore>.500"</bore>
                    <bell>8", fiberglass (red)</bell>
                    <key>Bb</key>
                    <slide>10/10</slide>
                    <cost>$150</cost>
                    <year>2011</year>
                </values>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <p>
                            This horn seriously looks like a toy. It is made almost entirely out of fiberglass, save the brass slide stockings.
                            It will never get too cold to touch, and it will never dent. The sound is very much like a brass trombone, but not
                            perfect. There is a significant lack of projection and resonance. The sound feels "dead", and you have to push much
                            harder to get an equivalent amount of sound as you would on a metal horn.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                </with-image>
            </section>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>