<page parent="lists">
    <title>Lists - Projects</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            Here are some things I've been working on, as well as some stuff on the backburner.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sidebar heading="Other Lists">
        <sections>
            <list id="Computer Related">
                <description>
                    <p>
                        The typical hacker will always be working on <i space-after="false">something</i>, even if they haven't actually put any work into
                        that something for years. Software projects are <b>never</b> complete.
                    </p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Project</column>
                    <column width="20%">Status</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>timski.info</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>In Progress (permanently)</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>No hacker's page would be complete without a quip about self-reference!</columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>FFVII Battle Simulator</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>On Hold</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            Written entirely in C# and Lua using GTK#, I've designed this simulator to be as extensible and scriptable as possible.
                            No graphics support -- backend only. I haven't worked much on this recently; still a lot of work that can be done though.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
            <list id="Home Related">
                <description>
                    <p>
                        I currently live with my parents in a house that my father built. I've put a lot of work into this house over the years,
                        along with my brothers, and of course my father.
                    </p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Project</column>
                    <column width="20%">Status</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Basement Bedroom/Bathroom</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Completed</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            I built a bedroom and bathroom in my parents' basement back in 2008 with
                            the help of my father. This is what I call my living space, along with the "den"--the "living room" of the basement.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Loft Conversion</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Completed (mostly)</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            The house needed a new roof. The old roof was over 20 years old, and leaked in a few places because of destructive ice
                            dams throughout every winter. We replaced the worse half of the roof in fall 2011, and we finished the other half in spring
                            2012. We also raised the peak by about a foot, and continued the roof at a constant angle out to the soffet (unlike the previous
                            design which used two different pitches, like a barn). This effectively removed the dormers from the bedrooms on the top floor of
                            the house, adding a foot and a half to their outer footprint. We even have some attic space now, whereas there
                            was barely room to crawl before.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
            <list id="Music Related">
                <description>
                    <p>

                    </p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Project</column>
                    <column width="20%">Status</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>My Hammond Organ</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>On Hold</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            My Hammond is a model RT-2. I stripped the pedal mechanisms and dismantled them, since they hardly worked, were needlessly heavy, and
                            unnecessary. I built a custom cabinet for the guts of the organ (not pictured) and burned the old one. Someday I'll build another, prettier, lighter cabinet, because the
                            aforementioned custom cabinet was put together in haste. I would like to rewire the tonewheels so the organ can be more portable, but that would be a massive undertaking.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Pinkie</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Completed</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            When I bought this guitar, it looked like <l space-after="false" href="/gallery/heap/tiger.jpg">this</l>. I stripped off the tiger fur and
                            painted it pink so that now it looks something like <l space-after="false" href="/gallery/heap/pinkie.jpg">this</l>. I more recently rebuilt the electronics
                            using Lace Sensor Gold pickups, and replaced the black pickguard with a white one. I want to repaint it once more and lacquer it. Someday I will
                            replace the neck with a Fender Strat neck, then Pinkie will be a full-fledged strat.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>
