<page parent="lists">
    <title>Lists - TV</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            Here are some <l href="../lists.html">lists</l> pertaining to TV.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sidebar heading="Other Lists">
        <sections>
            <list id="TV Shows">
                <description>
                    <p>
                        I watch TV on occasion. Actually, I don't exactly have the means to watch cable TV anymore since Comcast switched
                        to a digital signal or whatever. That's all well and good because when I move out I'm not going to be getting cable service.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Personally, I think there's a lot of crap on TV today. I find it harder and harder
                        to flip through the channels and find something I'm willing to watch at any given point during the day.
                        That's bizarre, seeing as how there are more channels and more therefore more programming than there used to be.
                        Why is there so much less to watch?
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        I think by far the worst crap on TV today are the shows that try to merge the styles of reality TV and documentary.
                        Take Pawn Stars for example. I think that show is cool in concept. But it is clearly scripted, which is a disappointment.
                        But what I hate about the show the most is the annoying cutaways to the mock interviews, in which the character is facing just
                        off camera answering a question nobody asked in the most clich&#xe9; way possible. That drives me CRAZY. And there are a ton of
                        shows out there with the same format, and every one I've seen I've disliked.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Anyway, I usually just watch shows on TiVo. Here are some of my favorite shows.
                    </p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="25%">Show Title</column>
                    <column width="75%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>South Park</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            My favorite show on television. I love the satire and political/social commentary, but the
                            fact that it's hilarious is certainly the show's greatest quality. I think I know about as
                            much about this show as anyone.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Daily Show with Jon Stewart</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            Thanks to the magic of TiVo, I didn't miss a single episode from fall 2005 to fall 2010--when I ended up going without cable for 8 months.
                            I got back on the wagon around May 2011, but I've once again cut the cable cord, so I'll only be seeing it when I get the chance.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>
                            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louie_(TV_series)">Louie</a>
                        </columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            This show is bizzarely humorous. Louis C.K., head writer/director/producer, has an odd wit that
                            is very easy to relate to, but his ideas are almost always pulled out of the stratosphere. This
                            show breaks all the norms of a situational comedy.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>
                            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aqua_Teen_Hunger_Force">Aqua Teen Hunger Force</a>
                            <i prefix=" ">(a.k.a. Aqua Unit Patrol Squad 1)</i>
                        </columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            This show is literally off the wall. It is full of non-sequiters and very often makes no sense
                            whatsoever, but the absurdity adds to the hilarity. The characters (and the voice actors backing
                            them) are consistently funny, especially <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Brutananadilewski">Carl Brutananadilewski</a>.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Family Guy</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            The best fart joke comedy TV has yet offered. However, its humor value has slipped in recent years.
                            <b>In general,</b> the older the episode, the more I like it.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Law &amp; Order</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            I've watched this show for years. Nowadays, it's a treat whenever an old episode comes on (such as one with Ben Stone), since after
                            19 seasons they tend to show more recent stuff. <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_McCoy">Jack McCoy</a> is one of my
                            favorite characters of all time.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>

            <list id="Notable South Park Episodes">
                <description>
                    <p>
                        I love <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Park">South Park</a>. Eventually I'm going to flesh this list out into a
                        review website on the series, but that will take some time that I don't currently have.
                        In the meantime, here are some of my favorite episodes and reasons why.
                    </p>
                    <p>My favorite episodes tend to be favorites for some common reasons:</p>
                    <ol>
                        <li>Mostly set in the elementary school, dealing with just the kids and their lives</li>
                        <li>Excellent satire</li>
                    </ol>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Episode Title</column>
                    <column width="20%">Season#-Episode#</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Tweek vs. Craig</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>3-5</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            The Mr. Adler scenes are a little odd, I'll admit. But the premise of the fight, basically a bet
                            between the main Four with Tweek and Craig caught in the middle, is hilarious. The sub-plot with
                            Kenny taking home ec instead of shop class is also very fitting.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Jewbilee</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>3-9</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            I am actually a big Kenny fan, and in this episode, he has to fake being a Jew in order to
                            go to a camp for Jewish kids with Kyle. I love the fact that you can clearly decipher what Kenny
                            is saying without the other characters having to repeat it, as in other episodes. Even full
                            sentences like "How do I do that?" are clear enough out of context to make sense. Moses is one of
                            my favorite South Park characters; we see him later in Super Best Friends.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Cartman Joins NAMBLA</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>4-6</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            The fact that the show is plotted mainly around elementary school kids is generally one of the
                            funniest building blocks of the show, because the na&#239;vet&#233; opens up different ways to look at
                            very seriously wrong things in the world, like NAMBLA. This episode exploits Cartman's naivety:
                            he joins NAMBLA because he thinks he is too mature for his kid friends and these cool, older men
                            welcome him in with open arms.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Towelie</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>5-8</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            This is probably the most self-aware episode of its time. A ridiculous, derp-quality character
                            is introduced named Towelie, and he is by far "the worst character ever", but by that same token,
                            he is also the best. During this whole episode the kids want nothing other than to get their Okama Game
                            Sphere back so that they can continue playing Thirst for Blood, but in the meanwhile they have to
                            suffer through one of the silliest, most contrived plot their writers have conceived yet!
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Asspen</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>6-2</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            By this point in the series, the writers had successfully established a reputation for satire, to the
                            point where they can write a satire about anything and nothing all at once. I can't tell if this episode
                            is a direct satire of a specific story, or if it's just a wrapper for
                            a bunch of lame stories with a similar storyline. Either way, the grief is clear, and anyone can relate.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Raisins</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>7-14</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            It is in this awesome episode that we first meet the Goth Kids, a group of which Stan briefly becomes a
                            member. It's so sad watching Butters spend all his money on a slimey Raisins girl, but at the same time
                            it is a vicious satire exposing the unfortunate thin line separating sexuality and good food service.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Quest for Ratings</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>8-11</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                The kids are in some sort of TV production course and are producing a school news program. However,
                                they find themselves losing in the ratings to Craig's "Animals Close Up With a Wide-Angle Lens", which
                                is exactly what it sounds like. So they beef up their news program with flashy graphics, lies about celebrities,
                                and stories that make people feel like they have to watch the show or they'll die (just like real news
                                programs).
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                It's even funnier to note that Trey Parker said of this episode, "...this was the first time we were
                                officially...out of ideas." Oh the irony.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Losing Edge</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>9-5</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                The kids are all playing baseball all summer in the state tournament circuit, and they hate every minute of it.
                                They want to lose so that their season will end, but every other team in the league wants the same
                                thing. The teams find themselves battling to see who can lose. An ingenious take on kids sports.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The parents, on the other hand, love every minute of their kids' success, especially Randy, who always
                                gets into fights with other drunk dads at the games. He is speechless to find out that he is going to get
                                to fight in the State Championship game.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>With Apologies to Jesse Jackson</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>11-1</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                The first and second times I watched this episode (different audiences), everyone in the room found themselves
                                gasping for air after laughing uncontrollably at the opening sequence. What an INCREDIBLE season premiere
                                to have seen with all of my friends in our freshman year apartment.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The List</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>11-14</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            Another episode based almost solely around just the kids and their lives at the elementary school.
                            That's not the <i>only</i> reason I like it, but it's a good reason. Does that sparkle with you?
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Major Boobage</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>12-3</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            This episode has so much to offer: Kenny doing drugs (sniffing cat pee), Cartman keeping a safe-house during
                            the cat holocaust, an Eliot Spitzer-themed public apology performed by Gerold Broflovski, and a
                            <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heavy_Metal_(film)">Heavy Metal</a>
                            parody, both in music and animation. I love it when Butters tries to comfort Kenny while he detoxes.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Ungroundable</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>12-14</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            This episode forces you to relate to the Goth kids, of all people, in their contempt for "Vamp" kids--kids who think
                            it's cool to dress up like vampires. With the recent vampire craze, for those of us thinking, "seriously, what's the
                            deal?", this episode shines brightly through the dark with a clear message: anyone who likes to dress up like a vampire is a douchebag.
                            Here, the writers again play on the na&#239;vet&#233; of the characters, specifically Butters. Butters is "transformed"
                            into a vampire and doesn't realize that he's still in fact a human, and goes without food because he thinks he
                            needs to consume only blood. He even goes so far as to give Cartman a hickey trying to suck his blood, never having
                            even bitten into him.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Pinewood Derby</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>13-6</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            The opening sequence of Stan and Randy preparing for and subsequently winning the Pinewood Derby is probably
                            my favorite beginning to any South Park episode, with the opening to "With Apologies to Jesse Jackson" being
                            a very close second. I love the scene when the FBI first comes to visit Randy.
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>You Have 0 Friends</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>14-4</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            Nothing has ever sufficed in expressing my hatred of Facebook better than this episode. It is
                            also brilliantly written. In this episode, I am Stan. And to quote Stan, "<i space-before="false">Fuck</i> Facebook, seriously!"
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>