<page parent="lists">
    <title>Lists - Video Games</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            I am a fan of video games, and have been for almost as long as I've been alive. One of my first toys
            growing up was a PC.
        </p>
        <p>
            I have a slightly addictive personality, which certainly comes out when playing games. I get addicted to
            one game and play it until completion or boredom. Then I put it on the shelf, wait a while (months to years),
            and then pick it up again.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sidebar heading="Other Lists">
        <sections>

            <list id="My Favorite Games">
                <description>
                    <p>These are my favorite games of all time.</p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Game</column>
                    <column width="20%">Platform</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Final Fantasy VII</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PlayStation</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <a name="ff7"></a>
                            <p>
                                I can't say enough about the game that changed my life. Nine playable characters complete with
                                unique, intertwining backstories; four complete CDs worth of brilliantly composed soundtrack;
                                50+ hours of gameplay; magic, swords, and guns all in the same context...
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                This game is a wonderful fantasy. It is so extensive that it takes multiple play-throughs to
                                fully understand what is going on--if you believe you can ever fully understand what is going on--yet so
                                enthralling that the story sticks with you from beginning to end.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I am a master of this game, through and through. I know how to get every item, learn every skill, and
                                travel to every area on the map. I have found so many ways to immortalize my party that battling enemies
                                has become trivial at the least.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Sega Genesis</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <a name="s3"></a>
                            <p>
                                I have quite literally played through this game in its entirety hundreds of times. I got into this game
                                by watching my brother Dave and his friend Kyle play it. I became Dave's apprentice, and as he learned
                                to play to perfection, so did I. There was one summer that I can remember playing S3&amp;K through from
                                beginning to end several times per day. I think Dave was on staff at summer camp that year, so I was
                                frequently lonely.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I hold S3&amp;K to be better than its predecessors for many reasons:
                            </p>
                            <ul>
                                <li>
                                    Better music
                                    <ul>
                                        <li class="nolabel">
                                            Not only is there <i>more</i> music in this game, but each act has its own unique track, unlike
                                            predecessors where all acts of the same zone had the same music.
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    More rings
                                    <ul>
                                        <li class="nolabel">
                                            More rings means more chances to pick up extra lives. When I play S2, I only very rarely reach 200 rings, and
                                            it's usually only right before getting injured and losing all of them. In S3&amp;K, I very often have 300+ rings,
                                            and sometimes even get into the 400s and 500s. I never remember what my record is, but I know it is <i>at least</i>
                                            in the 500s. I may or may not have seen a 600...I can't remember.
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Presence of a developed storyline
                                    <ul>
                                        <li class="nolabel">
                                            The game actually has <i>two</i> storylines; one for Sonic/Tails and one for Knuckles. Throughout both, there
                                            are definitive plot points and a developed storyline, even if it isn't always clear what that story is. Also, unlike
                                            in previous games, S3&amp;K features transitions between zones, so when you go from a hill covered in mushrooms to a
                                            flying fortress in the sky, you don't wonder what the hell just happened.
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Emeralds
                                    <ul>
                                        <li class="nolabel">
                                            Not only are there two sets of Emeralds in this game (Chaos and Super), they are by far the most fun to
                                            obtain. First of all, you don't need 100, 50, or even <i>any</i> rings to enter a special stage. This is a
                                            huge pain in the ass throughout Sonic 2, as you have to have 50 rings before hitting a star post in order
                                            to enter a special stage, and when you exit it, your ring count is reset to 0, meaning you have to recollect
                                            all your rings. Second, the special stages themselves are ridiculously fun and entertaining to play. Third, the
                                            fact that you finally get to play as Super Tails is one of my favorite parts of S3&amp;K.
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <a name="oot"></a>
                            <p>
                                Some would say that this is the greatest video game ever made. I tend to agree. It is certainly the quintessential Zelda game,
                                being the first one in 3D, the one that supposedly splits the series's timeline into <i space-after="false">
                                    <a href="http://zelda.wikia.com/wiki/Timeline">three</a>
                                </i>, and the one that describes the creation of the Triforce, Sacred Realm, and Hyrule itself.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
            <!--list id="&quot;The Classics&quot;">
            <description>
                <p>These are what I call &quot;classics&quot;.</p>
            </description>
            <listItems>
                <listItem>
                    <identity>Space Quest (series)</identity>
                    <descriptor>PC</descriptor>
                    <prose>
                        <p></p>
                    </prose>
                </listItem>
            </listItems>
        </list-->
            <list id="Video Games I've Played Through to Completion">
                <description>
                    <p>Here are some role-playing games that I've played through to completion.</p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Game</column>
                    <column width="20%">Platform</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Wizards and Warriors III</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This is a fantastic NES game. Your goal is to confront the evil king. You do this by acquiring
                                new identities with enhanced abilities which allow you to advance.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                You start off as a warrior named Kuros hunting for the evil wizard Malkil who has maliciously
                                taken the kingship of the city of Pideup from the Good King James. In order to make an assault on
                                the wizard's castle and free King James, Kuros must equip himself with the weapons of a knight,
                                tools which he lost shortly after his previous encounter with Malkil.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The game's world is split into three sections: the town, the
                                castle above it and the underground below. Each area has a guild: the town has a guild of thievery and stealth;
                                the underground, a guild of wizardry and sorcery; the castle, a guild of knighthood and valor. Each guild has three
                                levels, and the player must pass the tests of each level in order to gain that level's abilities and honors. Each new
                                ability allows you to enter a new section of the world, and typically, allows you to enter and attempt to pass the next
                                guild level. The final guild you enter is the 3rd level of the knight's guild, which gives you the sword and
                                armor necessary to defeat Malkil.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Final Fantasy VII</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PlayStation</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                See description <l space-after="false" href="#ff7">above</l>.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 and Knuckles</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Sega Genesis</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                See description <l space-after="false" href="#s3">above</l>.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This was the game that started it all. Like most NES games, this game is MUCH harder
                                than its 3D successors. The only way I found it pleasing to go through this game was
                                by looking stuff up online.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Zelda II: The Adventure of Link</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                Unlike most Zelda fans, <i>this</i> was the game I played over and over throughout
                                my childhood. And strangely enough, it has been called the black sheep of the series.
                                It is the only game in the series to have a primarily side-scrolling perspective, a number in its
                                title, extra lives, and an experience points system, among other things. Nevertheless, some
                                Zelda aspects introduced with this game became staples throughout
                                the series, such as items like the Hammer, the magic meter/spells, Dark/Shadow Link, the concept of different
                                parts of the Triforce (i.e. the Triforce of Courage), certain enemies, side-quests, etc.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                See description <l space-after="false" href="#oot">above</l>.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: Wind Waker</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>GameCube</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This game takes a lot of heat from Zelda fans. The overworld is a grid map of the ocean divided into
                                49 squares, and in each square is an island. Gameplay consists of a lot of sailing between those islands, which
                                is very time consuming and aggrevating to most players.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The dungeons in this game are not very good when compared to OOT or Twilight Princess.
                                And, there are only a small handful of dungeons to complete. The story is also lacking. Some Zelda fans
                                would agree that they would probably like the game <i>if</i> it weren't a Zelda game.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                Personally, I really like this game. The dungeons are disappointing, but the game still has so much to offer. The graphics
                                are very pleasing to look at. The fighting/controls are very comfortable and responsive. There are TONS of items to collect, and some unique items you
                                don't really find in the other games (Deku Leaf, Telescope, and the oh-so-useless Tingle Tuner).
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>GameCube</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                HOLY CRAP is this game beautiful. It might be the most graphically-attractive game made for the GameCube.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I think this game is the perfect union of its predecessors. It's like OOT on steroids, with more items, dungeons, and beauty.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Metroid: Prime</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>GameCube</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                I didn't really know what I was in for when I bought this game. I had seen
                                <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metroid_Prime_3:_Corruption">Corruption</a>
                                played before, so I knew that it was an exploratory RPG. But I had no idea what the Metroid series was about,
                                nor did I understand what the game would be like from beginning to end. I started to develop that idea early on, only to find
                                out as I progressed that I was horribly, horribly wrong.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I first played this game in the summer of 2008, when I was on my first co-op gig. Those summer nights
                                consisted of getting home from work, doing everything I needed to get done before the next day,
                                then getting high and playing Metroid. It was a great summer.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Half-Life</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PC</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                At the time, this was the longest game I had ever played. I got to enjoy it both while playing
                                and while watching Dave play it before me.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>
                            Half-Life<sup>2</sup>
                        </columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PC</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This game is EPIC. It is truly astounding how much work has gone into making this game
                                look real, not just in how it depicts textures and colors, but in how it depicts physical concepts
                                like motion, face muscles, and <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloom_(shader_effect)">bloom</a>.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Portal</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PC</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This game is seriously brilliant, both in design and concept. While
                                you never expect a game to be completely in touch with the world of
                                physics (especially not one that allows you to shoot wormhole-like
                                portals onto smooth surfaces like <i>Portal</i>), this game is
                                at its core a physics puzzle game. Use your understanding of physical reality to
                                navigate through this totally imaginative world of puzzles.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkatron</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Sega Genesis</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This game is "AWESOME". You take the role of a pair of the coolest, funkiest aliens in the
                                galaxy, and your job is to rid your home planet, Funkatron, of the pesky Earthlings that followed you back from your
                                most recent visit to Earth. You achieve this by catching the Earthlings and jars and tossing them on a ship back to Earth.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The music in this game is incredibly funky and creative. One of my favorite tracks, played whenever
                                you have to stroll through a flowery meadow, is called "Pasture Bedtime". Hilarious.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Goldeneye 007</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                Everyone who has ever played a video game has played this one. Goldeneye proved to be a seminal first person shooter,
                                and is probably responsible for the popularity and success of the multiplayer first person shooter genre. This is the
                                kind of game that friends could spend hour after hour shooting each other with varying combinations of weapons and rules
                                (including fighting in a slap-only sudden death match).
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Pok&#xe9;mon Snap</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                I don't care what anyone says, this game is a lot of fun to play.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Darwinia</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>PC</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                Darwinia is pretty unique. The graphics are elegant but simple, as is the gameplay. Strategy and timing are crucial to
                                success. But the whole concept of the plot and the world in which the game takes place is very creative.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I almost forgot I had even played this game.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
            <list id="Other Games I've Played">
                <description>
                    <p>Here are some other games I've played.</p>
                </description>
                <columns>
                    <column width="20%">Game</column>
                    <column width="20%">Platform</column>
                    <column width="60%">Comments</column>
                </columns>
                <listItems>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: A Link to the Past</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Super Nintendo / Game Boy Advance</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                At one time I was playing this game on Game Boy Advance, but that device was stolen from me in New York City,
                                and the game went with it. I don't remember how far I got, but needless to say I need to play this game again.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Game Boy</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                I'm so close to finishing this game that it hurts a little.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                I've had fun with this one. I like the items and the gameplay. I can't speak to the story yet since
                                I haven't finished it. I can't seem to memorize the overworld map no matter how hard I try.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Super Smash Brothers Melee</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>GameCube</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>

                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Super Smash Brothers Brawl</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Wii</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>

                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Mario Kart 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>Nintendo 64</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This game is OK. I like later incarnations better.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                Playing in 150cc mode is freaking hard.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                    <listItem>
                        <columnValue>Mario Kart: Double Dash!!</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>GameCube</columnValue>
                        <columnValue>
                            <p>
                                This is probably my favorite Mario Kart incarnation.
                            </p>
                        </columnValue>
                    </listItem>
                </listItems>
            </list>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>
