<page parent="index" suppressHomeLink="true" suppressParentLink="true" sortOrder="60">
    <title center="true">The Big Day</title>
    <sidebar>
        <p>
            <strong>Note:</strong> The wedding was a smashing success. For purposes of preserving history, this page will remain unchanged.
        </p>
        <sections suppressHomeLink="true" suppressParentLink="true">
            <section id="Event Details">
                <h3>Date/Time</h3>
                <p>Sunday, September 1, 2013</p>
                <values break-after="false">
                    <ceremony>1:00 PM</ceremony>
                    <reception>2:00 PM</reception>
                </values>
                <h3>Location</h3>
                <p>
                    Jenkins Residences
                    <br />15-17 Ferry Street
                    <br />Gloucester, MA
                    <br /><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?hl=en&amp;q=17+ferry+street,+gloucester+ma&amp;ie=UTF-8">Google Maps</a>
                </p>
                <h3>Directions</h3>
                <p>
                    <b>Planes:</b> Fly into Boston's Logan International Airport (BOS) or Manchester–Boston Regional Airport (MHT) in Manchester, NH.
                    If you need transportation from either airport, please contact Jamie or Timski at <i space-after="false">jamietimski@gmail.com</i>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>Trains:</b> The MBTA Commuter Rail stops in <a prefix=" " href="http://www.mbta.com/schedules_and_maps/rail/lines/stations/?stopId=71">downtown Gloucester</a>.
                    Ferry St is just about a mile up Washington Street.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <b>Automobiles:</b> Take MA Route 128 into Gloucester. At Grant Circle (the first rotary after the bridge), go 3/4 of the way
                    around and take the exit for 127 toward Annisquam (Washington Street, northbound). About
                    a third of a mile up, Ferry Street will be on the left.
                </p>
                <h3>Parking</h3>
                <ul>
                    <li>Limited "priority" parking will be available on Ferry Street nearby the Jenkins' residences </li>
                    <li>Additional limited parking will be available on other parts of Ferry Street, Sunset Hill Road, and Periwinkle Lane</li>
                    <li>Unrestricted parking will be available on Washington Street</li>
                    <hidden>Additional limited parking will be available across the street from 15 Ferry on the grass</hidden>
                </ul>
                <h3>Attire</h3>
                <p>
                    Expected attire should be "dressy casual". That means wear clothes that are comfortable for an all-day cookout,
                    but will look nice in pictures. The reception and ceremony will both take place on the grass, so shoes with heels
                    are not recommended. The lovely couple probably won't be wearing footwear, so you won't have to either!
                </p>
            </section>
            <section id="Accomodations">
                <p>
                    <b>Limited</b> camping space will be available at the Jenkins residences on the night of the reception. Some
                    spare tents and other camping gear will also be available. Please contact Jamie or Timski at <i>jamietimski@gmail.com</i> 
                    if you would like space or equipment reserved for you.
                </p>
                <p>
                    If you are looking for hotels near Gloucester, MA, you can try <a prefix=' ' href='http://www.capeannvacations.com/Hotel.cfm'>capeannvacations.com</a>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    We are still researching other local accomodations. We will post this information as soon as we have it!
                </p>
            </section>
            <section id="Refreshments and Facilities">
                <h3>Food</h3>
                <p>
                    Food will be provided as a buffet.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Catering will be primarily provided by <a prefix=" " href="http://thepigkahuna.com/">The Pig Kahuna</a>. They will
                    be slow roasting a pig on-site, in addition to BBQ chicken breast, corn on the cob, fruit salad, garden salad, and corn bread.
                    The Pig Kahuna will also provide a vegetarian dish.
                    In addition, hot dogs will be available for kids and other young folk.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Beans, macaroni, and cole slaw in large quantities will be provided by family.
                </p>
                <p>
                    The wedding cake will be provided by Jenn Klopotoski (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/CakesByJennK">Cakes by Jenn</a>).
                </p>
                <p>
                    There will be no seating arrangement. Tables, chairs, and tents will be available throughout the yard for all to use.
                </p>
                <h3>Drink</h3>
                <p>
                    The lovely couple will be brewing and preparing kegs of beer for guests to enjoy. There will be various options available.
                    So far four recipies are on the table, which are all being attempted this winter:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <i>Afternoon DeLite</i><ul>
                            <li>light/cream ale</li>
                            <li>low <a prefix=" " href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alcohol_by_volume">ABV</a>, low <a prefix=" " href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Bitterness_Units_scale#Bitterness">IBU</a>                            
                        </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Sunflower Weiss</i><ul>
                            <li>Honey Weissbier</li>
                            <li>medium ABV, low IBU</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Hoppily Ever After</i><ul>
                            <li>American Pale Ale</li>
                            <li>medium ABV, high IBU</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <i>Love Drunk</i><ul>
                            <li>Belgian Tripel</li>
                            <li>high ABV, low IBU</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    Wine will also be provided.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Juice, soda, water, and other non-alcoholic beverages will be provided.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Liquor will not be stocked. If you want to mix a cocktail, you'll have to bring the booze!
                </p>
                <h3>Facilities</h3>
                <p>
                    A bathroom trailer (a.k.a. <a prefix=" " href="http://www.unitedsiteservices.com/product/portalisa-restroom-trailer-rental">PortaLisa</a>) will be on site.
                </p>
            </section>
            <section id="Entertainment">
                <p>
                    Music during the ceremony will be provided by <a prefix=" " href="http://peterfedeleguitar.com/fr_home.cfm">Peter Fedele</a>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Entertainment during the reception will be provided by <a prefix=" " href="https://www.facebook.com/AllGoodFeelGood">All Good Feel Good Collective</a>.
                </p>
            </section>
            <section id="Campfire">
                <p>
                    As the afternoon transitions into evening, a campfire will be lit. It will most likely burn into the night and continue to glow the next
                    morning. <b>Warning:</b> there may be acoustic guitars and/or sparklers.
                </p>
            </section>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>
