<page parent="index" suppressHomeLink="true" suppressParentLink="true" sortOrder="40">
    <title center="true">Wedding Party</title>
    <sidebar>
        <p>
            If the phrase "wedding party" doesn't sound redundant to you, then you don't know how to wedding!
        </p>
        <br />
        <br />
        <sections suppressHomeLink="true" suppressParentLink="true">
            <section id="Jamie's Side">
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="Jackie"></a>
                        <h3>Jacqueline Michelle Gunnell</h3>
                        <p>
                            Jackie will be Jamie's maid of honor, and will be paired with <l space-after="false" href="#Robbie">Robbie</l>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            In middle school, Jamie referred to Jackie as her friend David's "annoying red-headed little sister." But as Jamie spent more and more time 
                            hanging out with David (with Jackie often tagging along), Jamie and Jackie eventually grew to become inseparable. Their antics, inside jokes,
                            and adventures (including road trips to New York, college dances, and fun times at Walmart and Arby's in Beloit, WI) put their friendship on 
                            par with Lucy and Ethel (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Love_Lucy">I Love Lucy</a>) or Cher and Deon 
                            (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clueless_(film)">Clueless</a>). Even though they now live over 1,000 miles apart, thanks to smartphones,
                            Facebook, and Words with Friends, their friendship continues to blossom. Jamie did double duty at Jackie's wedding in September, 2010 as 
                            officiant and maid of honor, and she couldn't be more excited to have Jackie return the favor...or at least half of it!
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/jackie.jpg</src>
                        <caption>Jackie with her husband Jake</caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="Phil"></a>
                        <h3>Philip Aaron Siegel</h3>
                        <p>
                            Phil will be Jamie's only bridesman. What an honor! He will be paired with <l space-after="false" href="#CousinPhil">Cousin Phil</l>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Phil was one of the first people Jamie met during her freshman year at Northwestern University. They both lived in the Communications Residential 
                            College (CRC) and bonded over their love of <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dawson%27s_Creek">Dawson's Creek</a>,
                            <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clueless_(film)">Clueless</a>, and
                            <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Will_and_grace">Will and Grace</a>. During college, Phil was Jamie's lunch and shopping companion,
                            dance marathon partner, and date to Chi Omega and Sigma Alpha Iota formals. In the years since, even though distance has often separated them, 
                            Jamie and Phil's friendship has strengthened during Thanksgiving meals in England and New York, spring break vacations in Barcelona and Florida, 
                            Halloween and New Year's adventures in California, annual Columbus Day apple picking in Massachusetts, and homecomings in Chicago.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/phil.jpg</src>
                        <caption>Phil (right) with his partner Mike</caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="Jes"></a>
                        <h3>Jessica Legendre</h3>
                        <p>
                            Jes will round out Jamie's side, and will be paired with her fianc&#233; <l space-after="false" href="#Al">Al</l>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            On one of Jamie and Timski's first dates, Timski brought her to Jes and <l href="#Al">Al's</l> house to hang out. As soon as Jamie met Jes,
                            she knew they would quickly become friends. Jamie enjoys spending time with Jes (and Al!) kayaking,
                            dancing at <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.timski.info/pages/bands.html#The Runaround Sound">Runaround</a> gigs,
                            bowling,
                            trying new beers,
                            attending <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.timski.info/pages/bands.html#Cape Ann Big Band">CABB</a> concerts,
                            planning double dates,
                            hosting dinner parties,
                            and playing <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Settlers_of_Catan">Settlers of Catan</a>. 
                            Especially when she is homesick and misses her Midwestern friends, Jamie is very thankful to have Jes in her life, and of course in the bridal party!
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/jes.jpg</src>
                        <caption>
                            Jamie, Timski, and Jes
                        </caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
            <section id="Timski's Side">
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="Robbie"></a>
                        <h3>Robert Andrew Klopotoski, Jr.</h3>
                        <p>
                            Robbie will be Timski's best man, and will be paired with <l space-after="false" href="#Jackie">Jackie</l>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Robbie is Timski's oldest brother. Timski has been following Rob's lead since he was little (or perhaps riding his coattails), first by taking up the trumpet in elementary school 
                            (though Timski would go on to taking up the trombone instead), and later by attending Northeastern University in the College of Computer and Information Science.
                            Rob's unbiased advice and superior knowledge of the world have helped to guide Timski into adulthood.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/robbie.jpg</src>
                        <caption>Robbie and his wife Jenn</caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="CousinPhil"></a>
                        <h3>Phillip Allan Jenkins, Jr.</h3>
                        <p>
                            Phil will be one of Timski's groomsmen, and will be paired with...<l space-before="false" space-after="false" href="#Phil">Phil</l>!
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Phil is Timski's first cousin on his mother's side. He proudly goes by "Cousin Phil", even in non-family contexts. Phil began his life
                            in Gloucester but moved to Medford, MA as a child. He and Timski have spent a lot of time together, but the real debauchery started
                            the day Phil turned 21 with an epic bar crawl in downtown Gloucester. As Jenkinses, Phil and Timski share a passion for the ocean, classic 
                            rock, and a really good party.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Phil was present the day that Jamie and Timski met. Timski's decision to get Jamie's contact information was partly due to Phil egging him on.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/cousinPhil.jpg</src>
                        <caption>Phil donning his best t-shirt</caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
                <with-image>
                    <text>
                        <a name="Al"></a>
                        <h3>Alessandro Delisi</h3>
                        <p>
                            Al will round out Timski's groomsmen, and will be paired with his fianc&#233; <l space-after="false" href="#Jes">Jes</l>.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            Al and Timski have known each other since middle school through the school band, but they really started to get to know each other 
                            through the high school stage band The Docksiders. These days, Al and Timski play together in the 
                            <a prefix=" " href="http://www.timski.info/pages/bands.html#Cape Ann Big Band">Cape Ann Big Band</a>.
                        </p>
                    </text>
                    <image>
                        <src>/gallery/heap/al.jpg</src>
                        <caption>
                            Al with <l space-after="false" href="#Jes">Jes</l>
                        </caption>
                    </image>
                </with-image>
            </section>
        </sections>
    </sidebar>
</page>
