<page>
    <title>Memoirs - Dave</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            So yes, my brother (Dave) is dating my ex (Chelsea). Long story. Deep breath. Go.
        </p>
        <p>
            It all started when dave met Diana, his wife. That was an absurdly long time ago, like 12 years,
            because they met in high school. No one in my family really understood their relationship, and
            when it came up that they were getting married, we really went after Dave to make sure he thought
            he was making the right choice. I can remember specifically telling him not to get married, that
            he was just going with it because 1) his father and older brother both married their high school
            sweethearts, 2) the familiar is easier and safer for him to handle, 3) a breakup would mean
            hurting Diana, and hurting someone is just about the worst thing in the world you can do (if
            your mind works like Dave's, or mine--we're very similar). He convinced himself that he would be
            able to be happy by making his wife happy, and ended up getting married for all the wrong
            reasons. Of course, he only admitted to all this recently during his mental breakdown. More on
            that later.
        </p>
        <p>
            His mother in law? Bat-shit crazy. And a total bitch. And his destiny was to live in his
            mother-in-law's house with his wife and son and future children while she lives in the in-law
            apartment Dave was to build on the side of the house. No way that living situation would have
            worked out.
        </p>
        <p>
            Chelsea. We dated during our senior year in high school, and broke up just over 5 years ago. It
            was a horrible breakup, and she didn't take it well. I chose to break contact with her. She
            reached out to different members of my family, because we are supportive and great in number--as
            opposed to her dysfunctional family--and she had become attached. She soon became close with my
            then-future sister-in-law (Diana), and was even in Dave and Diana's wedding. I was Dave's best
            man #2 (our older brother Rob was best man #1). Chelsea and I had only kind of reconciled by
            that point, and it was horribly awkward. Over the next couple of years things evened out a
            little bit between us, and the three of them were tight. Back in January, I started to notice
            that Dave's feelings were changing. Like I said before, him and I think a whole lot alike, and
            I noticed his behavior change better than anyone else. I told people in private, "I think
            Dave's falling in love with Chelsea" and they told me "you're crazy." But sure enough, I was
            right.
        </p>
        <p>
            Dave's mental condition started to deteriorate...
        </p>
    </header>
</page>