<page parent="timski">
    <title>About Timski</title>
    <sections>
        <section id="In Numbers">
            <values>
                <age>26</age>
                <height>~6'</height>
                <weight>~160 lbs</weight>
                <eyes>2</eyes>
                <hair>1</hair>
                <friends>
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Have_0_Friends">0</a>
                </friends>
                <emotions>6,121</emotions>
                <pets>3</pets>
                <children>0</children>
                <spouses>1</spouses>
                <siblings>4</siblings>
                <trombones>9 1/2</trombones>
            </values>
        </section>
        <section id="In Words">
            <p>
                I'm a self-declared nerd. I love to study astronomy, physics, calculi, combinatorics,
                computation theory, and computer science. I also am very intrigued by biology, religious
                history, human psychology, and the history of language. I ponder these subjects quite often.
            </p>
            <p>
                I love music. I am a self-taught musician who mainly plays trombone and organ. I picked up the
                organ in May 2008 for my (then) new band <l space-after="false" href="/pages/timski/bands.html#The Runaround Sound">The Runaround</l>.
                I have been playing trombone since 4th grade. I play sousaphone with the Boston
                Fireman's Band. I've also been known to bring my flute down to the church
                choir. I dabble on trumpet, guitar, bass guitar, didgeridoo, ocarina, ukulele, and other things. If it makes a tone, I like it.
                I refuse to study music academically.
            </p>
            <p>
                There is music for all times, all emotions, all people. While I'm driving I listen to 99.5 all classical, or one of about five cd's,
                depending on whether I want to get pumped out, mellow out, or sing along to something familiar. While I'm at work
                I listen to Renaissance vocal music. There's nothing like 6 part vocal polyphony.
                At home, it's rock. When I play piano I play mostly music from video games, but I know a little Beethoven.
                When I play with a group, it's almost always ska/reggae based. It's what I know, it's what I love. Playing with the
                <l href="/pages/timski/bands.html#Cape Ann Big Band">Big Band</l> gives me the chance to play some swing. Before I go
                out with people I listen to something like the Rx Bandits&apos; <em>...And the Battle Begun</em>, which is analogous to either
                doing cocaine or having a heart attack. <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.pandora.com">Pandora.com</a> is
                my best friend. I'm also pretty enamored with the Public Radio app.
            </p>
            <p>
                I think about stuff. A lot. And a lot of stuff. It's just the way I am. I enjoy many aspects of this fact, the most
                important being that I am becoming ever more aware of my own mind and how it works, which helps me live better and
                more easily. I learn best by example. I'm way more likely to remember a given number than a given word or name.
                I'm way more likely to remember an image than a given word or name. I'm also way more likely to remember mistakes over
                successes; mistakes evolve into rules.
            </p>
            <p>
                I have absolutely no concept of what other people are thinking.
            </p>
            <p>
                I like to think in the abstract and to generalize because it helps me to understand, or at least to remember. Working
                with computers so much has especially helped in this area, because in many ways I work like a computer. Classifications,
                especially hierarchies, help me to remember.
            </p>
            <p>
                Artistic creativity has always eluded me, the exception being music. I excel at things that are formulaic:
                mathematics, sciences, problem solving, and the like.
            </p>
            <p>
                I love beer. I hope to someday brew beer for a living with Jamie.
            </p>
            <p>
                I like to ride my bicycle. I wouldn't be seen in any kind of biking apparel, just gym shorts and a comfy t-shirt.
                I have a mountain bike that I bought at a yard sale for $20.
                I also have a pretty sweet old road bike that I bought for $100 off of Craigslist.
                I love riding this bike. It is an exhilarating feeling. I went by a police radar thing that tells you your speed and I
                was cruising at 19/20 mph; my top speed is well over that then, especially going down hills n such. Pretty cool I think!
            </p>
            <p>
                I love peanut butter and jelly sandwiches and buffalo chicken (not in the same meal).
            </p>
            <p>
                I am an uncle to five beautiful nieces (Katy, Kassidy, Megan, and <a prefix=" " href="/gallery/heap/karsyn.jpg">Karsyn</a>, Heather) and one nephew (Zacharry). I am part
                of an enormous and loving extended family. They have shaped and always will shape my life. It's tough for me to be away from them.
            </p>
            <p>
                I work full time as a software developer for <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.ebscohost.com">EBSCO Publishing</a> in Ipswich, MA.
                In May 2011 I completed undergraduate studies at <a prefix=" " href="http://www.neu.edu">Northeastern University</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                I am married to the Reverend Jamie Green Klopotoski. We live together at our house in Gloucester, MA. 
                Jamie runs a <a prefix=" " href="http://www.agapebeer.org/">beer blog</a>--check it out!
            </p>
            <p>
                Jamie and I have three cats. We adopted Bernie Worrell from a coworker of mine in August 2012.
                He looks like an oversized version of the 9 Lives cat (he's a big cat). We adopted two kittens from a shelter in Waltham,
                MA in February 2013. Turo Barley (the girl) is still with us, but Fuggles N. Tetnang (the boy) died on October 5, 2013. 
                We adopted a kitten from Cape Ann Animal Aid on September 26, 2014. 
            </p>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
