<page parent="timski">
    <title>Quotes</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            Here's <l href="/pages/timski/lists.html">another</l> place where I can create and manipulate data.
        </p>
        <p>Humor is at the top because I love funny things, plain and simple.</p>
    </header>
    <sections>
        <section id="Humor">
            <quote id="ironDick">
                <text>We are not establishing a democracy in this house! This is a dictatorship, and I rule with an iron dick!</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Master Shake</name>
                    <title>Aqua Teen Hunger Force</title>
                </credit>
            </quote>
            <quote id="generalFailure">
                <text>Who is General Failure and why is he reading my hard disk?</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Anonymous</name>
                </credit>
                <comments>
                    Ah, <a prefix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MS-DOS">DOS</a>. Childhood memories.
                </comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="eightDollars">
                <text>Stan, don't you know the first law of physics? Anything that's fun costs at least eight dollars.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Eric Cartman</name>
                    <title>South Park</title>
                </credit>
                <comments />
            </quote>
            <quote id="mantel">
                <text>If my parents had a mantel, I might be a completely different person.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>George Castanza</name>
                    <title>Seinfeld</title>
                </credit>
                <comments/>
            </quote>
            <quote id="connie">
                <text>
                    Connie, I think I have a theory about why you're such a bitch. You see, Connie,
                    you're popular because you developed early and started putting out when you were 12,
                    but now, you can't stand to look at yourself in the mirror because all you see is a
                    whore. So you pick on Meg to avoid the inevitable realization that once your body
                    is used up by age 19, you're gonna be a worn-out, chalky skinned, burlap sack that
                    even your stepdad won't want. How's that? Am I in the ball park?
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Brian Griffin</name>
                </credit>
                <comments>
                    My favorite Brian quote.
                </comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="enron">
                <text>You don't want another Enron? Here's your law: If a company, can't explain, in ONE SENTENCE....what it does....it's illegal.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Lewis Black</name>
                    <title>Comedian</title>
                </credit>
                <comments></comments>
            </quote>
            <dialogue id="dolphins">
                <line>
                    <text>Dude, dolphins are intelligent and friendly!</text>
                    <player>Wendy Testaburger</player>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <text>Intelligent and friendly on rye bread, with some mayonaise.</text>
                    <player>Eric Cartman</player>
                </line>
                <credit>South Park</credit>
                <comments>
                    I didn't really understand the term <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-sequiter">non-sequiter</a> (in the sense that I couldn't
                    produce or attribute one, despite having the definition close at hand) until I read this. A little light bulb went off in my head. Not to mention the fact that it's hilarious.
                </comments>
            </dialogue>
            <quote id="plants">
                <text>
                    I saw a commercial on TV that said, you can water your hard to reach plants with this product. Now who would make their
                    plants hard to reach? That seems so very mean. &quot;I know you need water, but I'm going to make you hard to reach.&quot; I
                    will throw water at you. Hopefully they will invent a product before you shrivel and die.
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Mitch Hedberg</name>
                    <title>Comedian</title>
                </credit>
                <comments>I was only introduced to this guy after he died.</comments>
            </quote>
            <dialogue id="80s">
                <line>
                    <text>I want to see what happens in the 70's and 80's!</text>
                    <player>Felicity</player>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <text>I checked into the 80's this morning. All there was was a gas shortage and a flock of seagulls. That's about it.</text>
                    <player>Austin Powers</player>
                </line>
                <credit>Austin Powers: The Spy Who Shagged Me</credit>
                <comments>
                    I was born in the 80's, but I'm still pretty sure nothing noteworthy happened in that decade.
                </comments>
            </dialogue>
        </section>
        <section id="Music">
            <dialogue id="singing">
                <line>
                    <text>I don't think you have a very good voice. But you're a singer. How do you do that?</text>
                    <player>David Byrne, interviewing himself</player>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <text>The better a singer's voice, the harder it is to believe what they're saying. So I use my faults to an advantage.</text>
                    <player>David Byrne</player>
                </line>
                <credit>
                    From a promotional interview for <span prefix=" " class="serif">
                        <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Making_Sense">Stop Making Sense</a>
                    </span>, in which yes, Byrne takes on various roles and interviews himself
                </credit>
            </dialogue>
            <quote>
                <text>If you can live without music for two or three days, then don't write – it might be better to spend the time with a girl or with a beer.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Henryk Górecki</name>
                    <birth>1933</birth>
                    <death>2010</death>
                    <title>Contemporary composer</title>
                </credit>
            </quote>
        </section>
        <section id="Life">
            <quote id="tolerance">
                <text>
                    Laws alone can not secure freedom of expression; in order that every man present his views without
                    penalty there must be spirit of tolerance in the entire population.
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Albert Einstein</name>
                    <title>Physicist</title>
                </credit>
                <comments>
                    This is true.
                </comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="rightThingPoorly">
                <text>
                    You have to go and do the right thing poorly before you can do it well. Whether it's
                    learning derivatives, or learning to be a leader, a manager, a parent, learning mathematics,
                    learning to ride a bicycle. You have to do it poorly first.
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Tom DeLong</name>
                    <title>Professor, Harvard Business</title>
                </credit>
                <comments>
                    Very hard for me to do sometimes.
                </comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="change">
                <text>It is not the strongest of the species that survives, nor the most intelligent that survives. It is the one that is the most adaptable to change.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Leon C. Megginson</name>
                    <title>Professor, LSU</title>
                </credit>
                <comments>
                    This quote is typically <a prefix=" " suffix=" " href="http://www.darwinproject.ac.uk/one-thing-darwin-didnt-say">misattributed</a> to Charles Darwin.
                </comments>
            </quote>
        </section>
        <section id="Love">
            <quote id="journeysEnd">
                <text>
                    Journeys end in lovers meeting,<br />Every wise man's son doth know.
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>William Shakespeare</name>
                </credit>
                <comments></comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="humanAffection">
                <text>We can live without religion and meditation, but we cannot survive without human affection.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Dalai Lama</name>
                </credit>
                <comments></comments>
            </quote>
        </section>
        <section id="Religion">
            <quote id="religionAsOpinion">
                <text>Truth, in matters of religion, is simply the opinion that has survived.</text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Oscar Wilde</name>
                    <title>Playwright</title>
                </credit>
                <comments></comments>
            </quote>
            <quote id="einsteinsReligion">
                <text>
                    Every one who is seriously involved in the pursuit of science becomes convinced that a spirit is manifest
                    in the laws of the Universe--a spirit vastly superior to that of man, and one in the face of which we with our
                    modest powers must feel humble. In this way the pursuit of science leads to a religious feeling of a special sort,
                    which is indeed quite different from the religiosity of someone more na&#xEF;ve.
                </text>
                <credit>
                    <name>Albert Einstein</name>
                    <title>the man</title>
                </credit>
                <comments></comments>
            </quote>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>