<page parent="timski">
    <title>Smilies</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            Smilies is a half-game, half-story concept I developed while doodling in my notebooks. I'm not
            sure when I drew my first Smiley, nor am I sure that I knew it was a Smiley at the time.
            The Smiley concept has grown over time in the back of my mind, but has not been officially
            drafted until now.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sections>
        <section id="Concept">
            <p>
                Smilies are a race of two-dimensional lifeforms. They take the shape of smiley faces, with some
                variants that will be discussed later. They reproduce, age, and interact with their environment like most lifeforms.
                They reproduce asexually, and have no gender. They do not die from old age.
            </p>
            <p>
                While Smileys may look friendly and happy, they are constantly at war. The sworn enemy of
                the Smiley is the Figure. Figures and Smileys have been at war for almost their entire history.
            </p>
            <p>
                Smileys fight off Figures with their eyes, which emit Figure-melting lasers. 
                A Figure need only to touch a Smiley to kill it.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Lifespan">
            <p>
                The lifespan of a Smiley runs through the following consecutive stages: infancy, adolescence, adulthood.
            </p>
            <h3>Infancy</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        Smileys are born out of a special kind of Smiley called "Breeders". New Smileys, 
                        called "Blinkers", emerge from Breeders as very small beings. They have 
                        one-dimensional dot-like eyes and a small, upturned smile. Blinkers' eyes
                        are not fully developed at birth, and cannot perform their intended function.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/blinker.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Blinker</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>Adolescence</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        After a short period of time, a Blinker's eyes will fully develop. 
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Young Smileys that can use their eyes are called Boomers. Boomers mature by 
                        exercising their eyes. The more they use their eyes, the faster they mature. 
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/boomer.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Boomer</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>Adulthood</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        When a Boomer has exercised its eyes enough, its eyes gain a dimension and 
                        become lines. Its mouth also grows. The result is a mature Smiley that is visually distinct
                        from what it was before. Mature Smileys are called "Adults", "Beamers", or sometimes just "Smileys".
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Adult Smileys are not so different from Boomers. They are larger, with more effective eyes,
                        but otherwise they serve the same role in society.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/beamer.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Beamer</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
        </section>
        <section id="Abilities">
            <p>
                There are several variations in the Smiley society.
            </p>
            <h3>Eyebrows</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        Eyebrows are an added ability developed by some Boomers and Beamers. Eyebrows
                        are a mark of increased intelligence, strength, speed, and vitality.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        The ratio of Browed Smileys to normal Smileys in a given society is determined by the
                        overall health of the society. When a society is fewer in number, more Smileys
                        will become browed in order to increase the chances of the society's survival.
                        In other words, the ratio changes as necessary in order to promote the overall health of 
                        the society.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Smileys with eyebrows are referred to as "Browed", as in "Browed Beamer".
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Browed Beamers can also become Breeders. This would only happen in very dire situations,
                        where the life of a whole society is threatened.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/beamerBrowed.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Browed Beamer</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>2D Eyes</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        Some Boomers use their eyes almost constantly from the time they are able. 
                        Rapid maturation leads to a different kind of adult eye than normal. Instead
                        of gaining one dimension, they gain two. 
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Smileys with two-dimensional eyes, called "Lookers", have 5x the offensive
                        strength of normal adults at the time of maturation.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/looker.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Looker</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>Dimples</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        Some Beamers are born leaders. As they age they cultivate understanding
                        of strategic warfare, effective planning, and resourceful management. Other
                        Smileys are drawn to their leadership, and they develop Dimples. Smileys that
                        weren't otherwise attracted to leadership qualities instinctively 
                        acknowledge the authority of Dimpled Smileys, also called "Leaders".
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Browed Leaders are an extraordinary asset to a Smiley society, as their
                        heightened abilities include their leadership qualities. This also makes
                        them a priority target of Figures.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Lookers cannot become Leaders, nor can Breeders.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/leader.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Leader</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>Open Mouth</h3>
            <with-image image-align="left">
                <text>
                    <p>
                        Some Smileys just aren't cut out to kill Figures.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        In a given society of Smileys, adult individuals can naturally be
                        selected to become Breeders whenever the Breeder population is low. As necessary, a
                        given adult Smiley will undergo a native transformation through
                        which its mouth will open wide, its size will greatly increase, 
                        and its eyes will cease to function (the sole exception being Browed
                        Breeders).
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Breeders will immediately start ejecting new Blinkers once their transformation
                        is complete.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Leaders cannot become Breeders. A Leader's role is far too
                        important to be sacrificed. Also, Lookers cannot become Breeders for
                        a smiliar reason.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/breeder.png</src>
                    <caption><i>Breeder</i></caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
