<page parent="season3">
    <title>Jewbilee</title>
    <values>
        <episode>9</episode>
        <season>3</season>
        <rating>10</rating>
    </values>
    <sections>
        <section id="Synopsis">
            <p>
                It's the night of the meteor shower, but this time we get to see what happens to both Kyle <em>and</em> Kenny.
                Kenny visits Kyle to see if he wants to camp out and watch the meteor shower, but Kyle is supposed to go to a
                Jewish camp with Ike called Jewbilee that night. Reluctantly at first, Kyle's parents decide it would be OK for Kenny to
                go to Jewbilee with Kyle, so they begin filling him in on the Jewish faith on the ride to the camp.
            </p>
            <p>
                At the camp, Kyle and Kenny participate in the regular Jewbilee activities, while Ike gets sent off with the Squirts.
                The Squirts have an encounter with the local bear, and the adventurous Squirt leader Schlomo, vying for his Chutzpah Badge,
                decides to take the Squirts on a mission to catch the bear. They set traps for the bear, but each trap backfires and
                results in the bear capturing a Squirt.
            </p>
            <p>
                During a meeting of the camp elders, Elder Garth from the synagogue of Anti-Semites starts to speak words of the coming
                of Haman, an adversary of the Jewish faith, which angers the other elders. He is thrown out of the meeting and told he
                is no longer welcome at Jewbilee. He swears that on the very same night, Haman will come and smite Moses and all of his
                followers.
            </p>
            <p>
                The Scouts and elders pray to Moses by the campfire, and he appears. The scouts bring him tidings of soap sculptures and
                popcorn necklackes while he awaits macaroni pictures from the Squirts, who are nowhere to be found. Moses notices that Kenny
                is not kosher, and banishes him from Jewbilee. While the scouts
                scramble to make the popcorn necklaces, Elder Garth approaches, reading from the book of Haman, and traps Moses in a conch
                shell. Elder Garth locks all the other elders and the scouts in the one of the buildings, then reads again from the book
                in order to summon Haman. It looks like all hope is lost for humanity.
            </p>
            <p>
                Meanwhile, Kenny gets captured by the bear and taken back to the bear's cave, where all the Squirts are celebrating the
                birthday of the bear's cub. Kenny informs the Squirts of the situation back at camp, and they return with the bear in order
                to free the elders and stop Elder Garth. While the Squirts free the other elders and the other scouts, Kenny breaks open
                the conch shell containing Moses with his head (killing himself in the process). Moses arises and immediately puts an end
                to Haman and Elder Garth. Moses declares that Jewbilee will henceforth be an annual celebration in honor of Kenny and his
                sacrifice for the Jewish faith.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="How Does Kenny Die?">
            <p>
                Kenny is killed when he breaks the conch shell open with his head.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Review">
            <p>
                This is one of my favorite episodes of all time. It is absurdly hilarious.
            </p>
            <p>
                Kenny is possibly my favorite of the four boys, and episodes like this one solidify that opinion. I find it interesting how
                despite the fact that his words are all muffled you can typically make out what he is saying. It's also hilarious that daytime
                censors still find it necessary to bleep out his muffled dialogue when he curses. There's also a (probably
                unintentional) allusion in this episode to the Mysterion story arc, in that Kenny happily crushes the conch shell with his head
                because the day <b>must</b> be saved, and he knows he'll just wake up the next morning completely fine.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Best Lines">
            <dialogue>
                <line>
                    <player>Kyle</player>
                    <text>Mom? Can Kenny go to Jewbilee with me?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Shiela Broflovski</player>
                    <text>Well, Kyle, Jewbilee is sort of a...special thing.</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Kyle</player>
                    <text>Oh. Kenny isn't special?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Kenny</player>
                    <text>Awww.</text>
                </line>
            </dialogue>
            <dialogue>
                <line>
                    <player>Chief Elder</player>
                    <text>Great and honorable Moses, what do you desire from us, your children?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Moses</player>
                    <text>I desire...I desire macaroni pictures.</text>
                </line>
            </dialogue>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
