<page parent="season3">
    <title>Tweek vs. Craig</title>
    <values>
        <episode>5</episode>
        <season>3</season>
        <rating>9</rating>
    </values>
    <sections>
        <section id="Synopsis">
            <p>
                Stan, Kyle, and Cartman attend their first day of Shop Class with the rest of the boys, where their new
                teacher Mr. Adler asks them all who is the biggest troublemaker. Stan and Kyle reply "Tweek", but Cartman
                swears that it's Craig. As they saw through pieces of scrap wood, the three boys enter a heated argument
                over who is tougher, Tweek or Craig. They decide that the only way to settle the dispute is to get
                Tweek and Craig to fight. Stan and Kyle convince Tweek that Craig wants to fight, and Cartman tells Craig
                a bunch of lies about Tweek to get him riled up. A fight is scheduled for that afternoon.
            </p>
            <p>
                Kenny, meanwhile, is sitting in his first day of Home Ec. with the girls of Mr. Garrison's class, where
                his teacher declares they "will be learning how to bake, sew, and make things that are lacy and pretty".
            </p>
            <p>
                After the first fight is called off because both Tweek and Craig went home to watch TV, the boys reschedule the fight
                for the next day. But, they have to postpone the fight again because neither Tweek nor Craig has ever been in
                a fight and they don't know what to do. Stan and Kyle proceed to have Jimbo teach Tweek boxing, while Cartman has
                Craig learn the art of Sumo wrestling. Eventually, the two end up fighting in the schoolyard. Meanwhile, Kenny gets transferred to shop
                class because his teacher "do[esn't] think the odds of [him] marrying a nice rich man in the future are very, well, good."
                The fight continues and casually migrates into the shop classroom, where Kenny is sawing through wood. The fight ends in Kenny being
                massacred by shop equipment.
            </p>
            <p>
                All the while, we find Mr. Adler experiencing vivid flashbacks (so vivid, in fact, that they are depicted in live action)
                about his wife who died in a plane crash while she was skywriting a message to him.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="How Does Kenny Die?">
            <p>
                Kenny is killed when he gets caught in the mitre saw, spun around at high velocity, and thrown into a box of old, rusty nails.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Review">
            <p>
                This one one of the first episodes that I noticed I really liked for a particular reason other than satire. In the later seasons,
                fewer and fewer episodes have had plots that revolve entirely around the children and their activities in and around school, without
                any hint of pop culture or satire creeping in.
                This episode is an early example of an episode with such a format, whereas The List is a good example of later episode. Whenever
                the plot focuses on the children, a subtle hilarity takes over where the show looks like a really indecent version of Peanuts.
            </p>
            <p>
                The best part about this episode is the press conference in the cafeteria. The boys are laying out the details of the fight
                and answering questions, when Kyle and Cartman start to get heated. They start fighting, and Stan and Kyle join in. Then
                Clyde declares, "Wow. Tweek and Craig really hate each other, huh? This should be a good fight." It reeks of irony! After all,
                no one gets excited when the four boys fight, and no one realizes that Tweek vs. Craig is just a disagreement fueled by a
                bet between the four boys.
            </p>
            <p>
                If I weren't so weirded out by the live action scenes, this episode would be rated a 10. It's not that they're bad, or even
                too over the top. They're just <i>weird!</i>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Best Lines">
            <dialogue>
                <line>
                    <player>Clyde</player>
                    <text>Hey, what's going on?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Kyle</player>
                    <text>Tweek and Craig are gonna fight.</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Clyde</player>
                    <text>
                        Really? Cool! <i>(pause)</i> It's funny because Tweek and Craig both went home about fifteen minutes ago.
                    </text>
                </line>
            </dialogue>
            <dialogue>
                <line>
                    <player>Mr. Adler</player>
                    <text>Now, does anybody know WHY you're in shop class? Yes?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Stan</player>
                    <text>Because we had to choose between this and Home Ec and we didn't wanna be sissies?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Mr. Adler</player>
                    <text>
                        Wrong! You are here because you are America's future! You may someday be doctors, or lawyers, or scientists. Most of you,
                        however, will be pumping gas, or cutting sheet metal, and that's why we have...shop class.
                    </text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Cartman</player>
                    <text>Oooooh!</text>
                </line>
            </dialogue>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
