<page parent="season1">
    <title>Cartman's Mom is a Dirty Slut</title>
    <values>
        <episode>13</episode>
        <season>1</season>
        <rating>8</rating>
    </values>
    <sections>
        <section id="Synopsis">
            <p>
                The boys are concerned when Cartman doesn't show up to school, and go to his house only to find him having tea in his back yard with his
                stuffed animals. They go to Mr. Mackey, who instructs them to videotape Cartman's behavior for further study. It turns out that Cartman is in
                distress because he has come to realize he is the only one among his friends without a father. He asks his mother who his father is, but Liane
                Cartman vaguely remembers the night during which Eric was conceived.
            </p>
            <p>
                Liane recalls that at the 12th Annual Drunken Barn Dance, she got really hammered before running into Chief Running Water, and assumed that he
                was the man who impregnated her. Cartman goes to the Chief who recalls that Liane went for Chef instead, and Chef then tells Cartman that Liane
                then went for Mr. Garrison. Cartman goes to the pub to confront Mr. Garrison, who admits to having sex with Liane that night, along with the rest
                of the patrons at the bar (including the women). The situation looks hopeless until Dr. Mephisto tells Eric he can do a DNA test to find the real
                answer, but it would cost a hefty $3,000.
            </p>
            <p>
                Meanwhile, the other boys decide to enter their video of Cartman having tea with his dolls in the America's Stupidest Home Videos competition
                after hearing about its $10,000 grand prize. They promise to give Cartman the money he needs for the DNA test, just before he watches the video
                broadcast all over America on primetime television. The video loses to another entry--a videotape of Kenny getting run over by a train filmed
                by Stan's grandfather--but the kids still get the $3,000 runner-up prize.
            </p>
            <p>
                Mephisto performs the DNA test against everyone who was present at the Drunken Barn Dance, and the results are left as a cliffhanger for the next season
                to resolve.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="How Does Kenny Die?">
            <p>
                Kenny is killed by a train after being dragged onto the tracks by Stan's go-kart.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Review">
            <p>
                The cliffhanger is intensified by the fact that the resolution is in the <a prefix=" " href="../season2/episode2.html">
                    <i space-before="false">second</i> episode of Season 2
                </a>, not  the first.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Best Lines">
            <dialogue>
                <line>
                    <player>Chief Running Water</player>
                    <text>Kid, I hate to break this to you, but your mother is what we Native Americans refer to as 'Bear with wide canyon'.</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Cartman</player>
                    <text>What do you mean?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Chief Running Water</player>
                    <text>She is 'Doe who cannot keep legs together'.</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Cartman</player>
                    <text>Huh?</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Chief Running Water</player>
                    <text>Your mom's a slut.</text>
                </line>
                <line>
                    <player>Cartman</player>
                    <text>HEY!</text>
                </line>
            </dialogue>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
