<page parent="index" suppressParentLink='true'>
    <title center="true">About Us</title>
    <sections suppressHomeLink="true" suppressParentLink="true">
        <section id="How We Met">
            <p>
                Preface: greatest story ever.
            </p>
            <h3>Timski's Backstory</h3>
            <p>
                On Thursday, May 10, 2012, Timski's cousin John invited him to a Red Sox game to take place later that night. Timski met John outside the
                park to get his ticket, and they went in and had a great time (despite Josh Beckett's abysmal outing). That weekend, Timski's grandmother
                designated him the holder of four more Red Sox tickets (this time on the Bud Deck) for a game to take place on Tuesday, May 15. The original
                claimants to the tickets all backed out, so Timski gave two to his aunt Davya, one to his cousin Lizzy, and kept the fourth. Everyone agreed
                to meet at the game, which was scheduled for 4:05 PM.
            </p>
            <p>
                The morning of the 15th, Timski had to get up early in order to leave work early to get to the game on time. He scrambled around with half
                an eye open, grabbed his keys/wallet/phone/ticket and rushed out the door. After work, he took the train to Boston and hopped on the T,
                arriving in Back Bay around 6:30 PM. It was then that Timski got a pit in his stomach, reached into his back pocket, and discovered that
                he had brought the wrong ticket; he had brought the ticket from the game on May 10th. It <i>looked</i> like a new ticket--no stub was
                missing because they don't rip the ticket anymore, they just scan it--but sure enough, it was the wrong one. It wasn't going to get him
                into the game, and there was no way to get the right ticket in time. He considered grabbing a ticket from a scalper just so that he wouldn't
                have to miss watching the game with cousin Lizzy. But it was starting to rain lightly, so he instead settled on getting a beer at a
                bar near Fenway. "Which bar?" Timski thought as he walked briskly down Lansdowne Street. "Bill's bar? No. Game On? Screw that. Cask'n Flagon? Hell no. Beer
                works? Works for me!"
            </p>
            <p>
                After the host greeted Timski with the typical "Can I see your ID?" he asked which bar he would be sitting at, the
                back one or the front one. Both bars were pretty sparse in clientele, so Timski chose the back bar, where there was a greater ratio of
                females. As the game got underway on the many LCD screens around the bar, Timski ordered a beer and sat at the back bar alone. People came
                and went all around him, including  one woman who sat in the adjacent stool drinking wine (at the Beer Works?) and playing that silly drawing game on her phone.
                Later on, around maybe the sixth inning, a nice looking woman approached the bar and sat on the stool two to the right of Timski. He
                figured if nothing else, she'd be fun to glance over at between pitches. But as he watched her stare at the beer menu with an eye like a
                searchlight, he started to think she may be even more interesting to talk to than to just look at. She was alone, and he was alone; with no
                wingmen on either side inducing conversation, he waited to see if the perfect icebreaking moment would pass.
            </p>
            <h3>Jamie's Backstory</h3>
            <p>
                In December 2011, Jamie attended a Christmas Party for the deacons from her church and spoke with Jim Conroy about brewing
                beer through most of the evening. Jamie expressed her interest in one day opening a brewery (though she had never actually brewed beer before). Jim described a place in
                Natick called "<a href="http://www.barleycorn.com">Barleycorn's</a>" where you can brew your own beer with their equipment, ingredients,
                recipes and advice. On Christmas Day, Jamie had dinner with the Conroy family and was presented a fabulous Christmas
                present--a gift certificate for brewing at Barleycorn's. On April 12, 2012, Jamie visited Barleycorn's and brewed a Trappist Tripel. During the three
                weeks of fermentation that followed, Jamie created a name for her beer--"First Love" (and future brewery--"Agape Brewing Company"), designed
                a label, purchased a domain name (<a href="http://www.agapebeer.org">agapebeer.org</a>) and started a beer blog to write
                about her adventures in beer making and tasting (as well as to advertise her future business). The blog debuted on May 2nd, 2012, and Jamie posted
                several entries about different beers she had tasted at beer festivals, restaurants, and bars.
            </p>
            <p>
                On Tuesday, May 15th, 2012, Jamie had plans to see Ingrid Michaelson in concert at the House of Blues with her friend Kimberly (whom she met
                through the Conroy family). When Kimberly suggested they meet for dinner and drinks beforehand, Jamie immediately knew where she wanted to go: Boston
                Beer Works--a brew pub that makes delicious beer, just down the block from the House of Blues. That night, Jamie ran into no traffic driving
                from work in Needham to Boston and immediately found a great parking spot on Comm Ave, so she was early (which is quite atypical for her).
                Kimberly was running a little late, so Jamie decided to grab a seat at the bar and order some beer. At the time, she did not notice the
                astonishingly handsome man sitting just two seats over from her. Since Jamie had just started her beer blog,
                she wanted to make sure she ordered beer that she had not yet had there. After meticulously consulting her beer excel spread sheet (where she
                lists, describes, and rates every beer she tries) on her phone and studying the menu, she decided to order a flight (4 samplers of: Boston Common,
                Mayflower Maibock, Haymarket Hefeweizen, and Buckeye Oatmeal Stout). When it arrived, she took a picture of the sampler in order to post it in her
                blog (which she did, <a prefix=" " href="http://www.agapebeer.org/post/23425344037/more-beer-works">here</a>).
            </p>
            <h3>The Introduction</h3>
            <p>
                Timski sat bewildered for a moment, before deciding to seize this unique opportunity to break the ice. He leaned over to Jamie and asked, "Did you just
                take a picture of your beer?" Jamie giggled and fessed up, and then explained that the picture was for the blog entry she would write about her visit to the
                Beer Works. Timski had recently been to Denver, and had taken a similar picture while tasting every beer at the Rock Bottom Brewery in LoDo. Feeling cocky, he
                produced his phone and showed Jamie the picture: "How about <i>this</i> picture?" She maliciously replied, "You know there's a Rock Bottom Brewery in Boston, right?"
                Embarrassed but not deterred, Timski continued to ask about Jamie's interest in beer.
            </p>
            <p>
                Before long, Kimberly arrived and sat between Timski and Jamie. The three conversed for a moment before Timski retreated back into his beer to allow
                the girls to enjoy the rest of their night. The two girls caught up in regular fashion, by discussing boys--specifically Jamie's recent dating adventures, including dates with a Catholic School teacher,
                the winner of Beauty and the Geek Season 4, and a friend of a friend. Inadvertently at first, Timski found himself
                still listening in on the girls' conversation. Jamie expressed to Kimberly how she was giving up dating because she was finding it incredibly difficult to find someone.
                At one point, Timski interjected: "here's to being single, because single people are the shit," and the three toasted.
            </p>
            <p>
                Eventually, Kimberly decided to "go to the bathroom" so that Jamie could continue talking to Timski. But to Jamie's misfortune, the Rex Sox game had ended,
                and Timski's family had arrived. He joined them at a nearby table for pizza just as Kimberly was making herself scarce.
            </p>
            <p>
                With Cousin Phil (who also attended the game) egging him on, Timski decided to talk to Jamie one last time to "seal the deal". He intended to just get the address of her blog as
                a single point of contact, but to his surprise Jamie offered her phone number. Timski left with his family on the T, and Jamie and Kimberly eventually went off to the House
                of Blues.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="The First Date">
            <a name="The Phone Call" />
            <h3>The Phone Call</h3>
            <p>
                Wednesday passed, and Thursday passed, and nothing came of the meeting. Jamie took a trip to New York to visit her brother Jeff and friend Melissa; Timski worked.
                Finally on Friday evening, while enjoying a week-ending beer by the campfire, Timski
                gathered up a bit of courage and gave Jamie a call. Jamie was excited to hear from him, and Timski was pleased. He asked if
                she wanted to go get a beer with him the next night, and suggested the Cape Ann Brewery in Gloucester, since he knew she hadn't been there yet. Jamie willingly accepted,
                and the two agreed to meet at 7:30 PM.
            </p>
            <h3>The Date</h3>
            <p>
                Jamie was still in New York on the day of the scheduled rendezvous due to an unfortunate towing incident. She drove back at 3am in order to be back in Needham for a 9am open house.
                It was one of the most exhausting commutes she has ever had, with traffic rerouted through podunky towns in Connecticut for road construction (because they <i>closed</i> I-95!)
                When she finally got to her apartment that afternoon, she took a nap and woke up an hour and a half before the date (resulting in a grand total of 8 hours of the sleep in the past 58 hours).
                She felt absolutely miserable, and now had only 30 minutes to get ready for the date. She considered calling to cancel but decided against it. She hurriedly got dressed,
                texted Timski to tell him she would be late, and set off for the hour long commute.
            </p>
            <p>
                Timski arrived first and waited at the host station for Jamie, though she didn't end up being as late as he expected. She greeted him happily with a hug, and the two found a
                seat at an indoor table. The Darryl Strawberries and Grand 27 were playing. Timski ordered a Sunrise Saison in his Mug Club
                mug, and Jamie ordered a flight consisting of Eclipse, Honey Pilsner, Dunkelweiss, Imperial Pumpkin Stout, Navigator, and Dead Eye IPA (which she also
                <a prefix=" " href="http://www.agapebeer.org/post/24088545381/gloucester-adventures">blogged about</a>). For dinner, they ordered a turkey leg appetizer,
                since neither of them were very hungry (besides, beer is food). They talked
                and laughed, and openly wondered how their meeting was even possible. They enjoyed tiramisu for dessert. Timski's friend Jesse was also at the bar that night, and he
                came over to introduce himself (he
                was actually present during <l space-after="false" href="#The Phone call">the phone call</l>). The night went by in a whir, and neither of the two seemed to want to leave.
                Right before Jamie was about to say goodbye for the evening, Timski suggested she come back to Ferry Street (where he was house-sitting for his aunt and uncle) for a campfire.
                Once again, Jamie willingly accepted, and the two departed in separate cars.
            </p>
            <p>
                Once back at Ferry Street, Timski and Jamie joined his uncle Peter, who was standing near the campfire, keeping it hot in anticipation of their arrival.
                Timski disappeared into the darkness of the backyard, and came back a moment later dragging a browned Christmas tree behind him. He threw it on the fire and it
                went up in an orange and yellow blaze. Jamie was shocked but excited, as it was a dangerous but beautiful sight. With the fire back in Timski's hands, Peter departed
                for the night and left the two lovebirds alone by the fire. By this point, Timski had taken Jamie into his arms.
                There was very little firewood left, and Timski had to keep throwing scraps in and stirring the fire to keep them warm. Eventually there was no fuel at all to burn, so the two went
                inside, in spite of Jamie's repeated claims of having to be at work very early the next morning. Once inside in the warm house, Timski sat at the piano and played for Jamie.
                They shared their first kiss (and their second, third, fourth...) and stood smiling at each other for a while. With great reluctance, Jamie finally decided to depart at 3:30 AM.
                After a final few kisses in the driveway, Jamie got in her car and made the hour-long drive back to Waltham.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="The Engagement">
            <p>
                Jamie and Timski spent most of the summer of 2012 together, but the crucial tests of their relationship came in the form of two
                getaway trips: first, a camping trip in NH with a large portion of Timski's family, and then a road trip to Milwaukee to visit with Jamie's
                closest friends. After returning from the road trip and allowing a couple of days to pass, Timski started itching to propose. He spilled
                the beans to his sister-in-law Jenn at lunch the following Monday, and the idea snowballed from there. By Tuesday evening, he had
                his plan put together.
            </p>
            <h3>The Ring</h3>
            <with-image>
                <text>
                    <p>
                        On Thursday that week, Jamie was to be at a meeting in the evening, and Timski was supposed to be at a softball game.
                        Timski sneakily decided this would be the perfect time to go buy the ring. Accompanied by his mother Maureen and Jenn, he headed to the Square One Mall in
                        Saugus, MA, which houses several jewelry stores.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        The first stop was Hannoush Jewelers, and it turned out to be the only stop that was necessary. The salesman, Frank, showed off a bunch of rings,
                        but the only one Timski was interested in was this petite ring with an unusual blue diamond. Frank, Maureen, and Jenn tried explaining to Timski
                        that an engagement ring is supposed to have a <i>real diamond</i> (you know, the colorless kind), wedding bands are important (and the one Timski
                        wanted wouldn't fit well with a wedding band), and other such things in order to help him find the right ring, but the little
                        ring with the blue diamond seemed to be absolutely but inexplicably perfect.
                        They searched other shops that night, but eventually came back to Hannoush, where Timski decided to take a risk and get the unusual ring.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/ring.jpg</src>
                    <caption>The engagement ring</caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>The Proposal</h3>
            <with-image>
                <text>
                    <p>
                        On the night of Friday, August 31 2012, Timski had a gig with his band <l href="/pages/bands.html#The Runaround Sound">The Runaround Sound</l> at
                        the <a prefix=" " href="http://www.capeannbrewing.com/">Cape Ann Brew Pub</a>. Since that was where he and Jamie had their first date, he thought it would be the
                        perfect time and place to propose.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Jamie arrived from work a little bit into the first set. Surprisingly, she didn't find it odd that most of Timski's immediate family was present, given that
                        they don't usually all come to his gigs. At the first set break, Timski greeted Jamie and asked if she wanted to go get some air outside.
                        They walked out onto the dock overlooking Gloucester's inner harbor; it was a gorgeous evening. There he pulled the ring out of his pocket and asked Jamie if she would marry him.
                        Cheers and camera flashes abounded from the pub as Jamie accepted.
                    </p>
                </text>
                <image>
                    <src>/gallery/heap/proposal.jpg</src>
                    <caption>The proposal</caption>
                </image>
            </with-image>
            <h3>The Party</h3>
            <p>
                The happy couple celebrated their engagement with a party at their residence on October 6, 2012. Unfortunately, everyone
                was too busy having fun to take pictures!
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="The Nuptials">
            <p>
                Jamie and Timski were married at the Jenkins residences in Gloucester on September 1, 2013.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="The Rest...">
            <p>...is history.</p>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
