<page parent="index" suppressParentLink='true'>
    <title>About This Site</title>
    <header>
        <p>
            Woo. Info on the site and my progress in developing the tools and the content that generate it. Updated sporatically.
        </p>
    </header>
    <sections>
        <entry id="9/5/2013">
            <p>
                Reorganizing the whole site to make space for Jamie!
            </p>
            <p>
                No longer generating the homepage using a special utility. Transform it like all the other pages.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="3/19/2012">
            <p>
                I've reorganized the pages into a true hierarchy. This allows each page to have a link to its parent.
            </p>
            <p>
                I've also restored the gallery.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="2/23/2012">
            <p>
                I've added some new pages under 'instruments'. I also updated the 'quotes' page.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="11/28/2011">
            <p>
                Major changes:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    TransformPages.exe
                    <ul>
                        <li>the one-to-one correspondence between page source (xml) and xslt file has been broken</li>
                        <li>some templates have been consolidated (lists, etc)</li>
                        <li>allow for a page index based off the entries in a specified subfolder (no page content)</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    GenerateIndex.exe
                    <ul>
                        <li>read entire page index from lookup</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    New Pages
                    <ul>
                        <li>lists\movies.html</li>
                        <li>lists\music.html</li>
                        <li>lists\tV.html</li>
                        <li>lists\videoGames.html</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Updated Pages
                    <ul>
                        <li>blog.html</li>
                        <li>calendars.html</li>
                        <li>siteLog.html (duh)</li>
                        <li>lists\projects.html</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </entry>
        <entry id="11/2/2011">
            <p>
                Been working on the TransformPages executable. I'm thinking of starting to review South Park episodes
                in the same manner as our dream to one day review all the Simpsons episodes. That being the case, I'm looking
                into more extensible methods for mass-transforming pages. Right now I use a one-to-one correspondence between
                an xml file and an xslt file to create a single html page. I'm going to loosen this requirement, first of all.
                Second, I'm going to try and restructure the site into a generic hierarchy, and attempt to make the already
                in place gallery and calendars pages fit into this hierarchy scheme.
            </p>
            <p>
                I also found it necessary (out of boredom?) to remove all usage of 'font' elements from the site and
                increase stylesheet usage. This required a lot more work than I had anticipated, and it has left me feeling that even
                a well managed site (like I thought mine was) is very unmanagable. How the internet ever scaled up, I have
                no idea. It just sucks that we'll never be fully away from HTML 1.0.
            </p>
            <p>
                Anyhow, I've updated some other stuffs too.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="10/17/2011">
            <p>
                Updated the following items:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>'Links' page</li>
                <li>'Facts' page</li>
                <li>
                    GenerateIndex.exe
                    <ul>
                        <li>slight change to the linking mechanism</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </entry>
        <entry id="5/31/2011">
            <p>
                Updated some stuff, including summer gigs.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="5/23/2011">
            <p>
                This update marks a huge step in this website's presence on the web. I now own the domain <span prefix=" " class="serif">timski.info</span>! I registered this domain through
                GoDaddy.com and got separate hosting through FatCow. I had to do some work on my end to get this all to work, mostly through updating my automated host script.
                Pretty soon I will host my brother's website, <i space-after="false">Sweet Movie Reviews</i>, on the same host as Timski. We still have a lot of work to do before that goes out though.
                Look for <a prefix=' ' suffix=' ' href="http://www.sweetreviews.net">sweetreviews.net</a> to be up and running in the [near] future.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="4/26/2011">
            <p>
                Overhaul of 'projects' page
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="4/25/2011">
            <p>
                Corrected Brian's name on bands page!
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="4/21/2011">
            <p>
                Updated the following items:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>show dates</li>
                <li>'Facts' page</li>
                <li>'Bands' page</li>
                <li>'Lists' page</li>
                <li>site log (duh)</li>
            </ul>
        </entry>
        <entry id="3/15/2011">
            <p>
                Added timestamp to all pages. Also updated the following items:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>show dates</li>
                <li>'Facts' page</li>
                <li>'Bands' page</li>
                <li>site log (duh)</li>
            </ul>
        </entry>
        <entry id="12/7/2010">
            <p>
                Retroactively added my parades for the last two Boston Firemans&apos; Band seasons.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="12/6/2010">
            <p>
                A few weeks ago I was working on another site, the upcoming <b space-after="false">badsimpsons.com</b>.
                I copied many of the materials from this site over to that one, mainly the C# web tools that I wrote.
                As part of the badsimpsons effort, I did an overhaul of webtools, removing many dependencies and making
                them more portable (primarily removing the DataManager component). I then rolled those changes back into
                this site's source.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="9/14/2010">
            <p>
                A few updates. The gallery will be down until I move to a different server. Gigs updated.
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="01/27/2010">
            <p>
                Added pictures of the kitties!!!
            </p>
        </entry>
        <entry id="01/15/2010">
            <p>
                Finally bothered to add logging to the site. This is the simplest mechanism I have found so far to 
                keep records of updates. Someday I'll have a git repository for that, but I'm waiting for the right
                operating system to come my way.
            </p>
            <p>
                DataManager component and WebTools suite are well integrated.
            </p>
            <p>
                The suite currently consists of the following tools:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>BatchCopy</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>uses a string->list lookup to copy files in batches to managed locations</li>
                </ul>
                <li>GenerateCalendars</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>generates calendar month web pages from scratch based on data files and lookups</li>
                    <li>events get added to the calendar based on event list files</li>
                </ul>
                <li>GenerateGallery</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>generates the image gallery web pages</li>
                </ul>
                <li>GenerateIndex</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>generates the homepage and links it to all the other pages</li>
                </ul>
                <li>TransformPages</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>transforms xml content into web pages</li>
                    <li>configured by DataManager</li>
                </ul>
                <li>WebTools</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>utility library for normalizing all the web content</li>
                </ul>
            </ul>
        </entry>
    </sections>

</page>
