<page parent="jamie">
    <title>About Jamie</title>
    <sections>
        <section id="In Numbers">
            <values>
                <age>29</age>
                <height>~5'7"</height>
                <pets>3</pets>
                <spouses>1</spouses>
                <siblings>1</siblings>
                <timesMoved>18</timesMoved>
                <statesVisited>39</statesVisited>
                <countriesVisited>9</countriesVisited>
                <planetsVisited>1</planetsVisited>
            </values>
        </section>
        <section id="In Words">
            <p>
                Jamie was raised in Wisconsin, but at age 12 she was abducted by aliens and spent the better part of her teenage years trying to escape 
                captivity in order to return to Earth. No, but seriously, Jamie did have a difficult childhood, but she covered up her troubles by being 
                overly involved in school, church, extra-curriculars, and work. At church, she was a member and leader of Sunday School, Youth Group, 
                and Choirs. In school, Jamie joined French Club, Math Team, the high school newspaper, Quiz Bowl and National Honor Society. Music was 
                also a huge part of her childhood. She played clarinet, bass clarinet, contra alto clarinet, bassoon, tenor saxophone, oboe and English
                horn in band and pit orchestras for Oklahoma, Annie, and Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat. Jamie also enjoyed acting--her 
                star role was playing Scrooge in the "Kids Fun and Drama" performance of The Christmas Carol.
            </p>
            <p>
                Despite a few setbacks in High School, Jamie graduated at the top of her class with a 4.0 GPA and headed off to Northwestern University in 
                Evanston, IL. During her college years, Jamie played Tenor Sax in Marching Band and Jazz Bands, Bassoon in Concert Band and Woodwind 
                Ensemble, and was Vice President of Membership of Sigma Alpha Iota, International Music Fraternity for Women. In 2006, she
                graduated cum laude with a B.A. in Religion and Jewish Studies.
            </p>
            <p>
                After graduation, Jamie moved to Massachusetts to attend Harvard Divinity School, where she studied youth ministry and interned at churches
                in Cape Cod and Groton, MA, and as Chaplin at Massachusetts General Hospital. She graduated with a Master's of Divinity in June, 2009 and 
                was ordained in November, 2009. She now considers herself finally in the "real world" with her first full time job at Congregational Church
                of Needham as Youth Minister, working with Sunday School, Youth Group, and an after school program she created called "The Center" 
                (<link no-space-before="true" no-space-after="true">www.myyouthcenter.org</link>).
            </p>
            <p>
                Jamie loves beer (drinking beer, making beer, talking about beer) and has a dream of one day starting her own brewery. Check out her
                beer blog at <link no-space-after="true">www.agapebeer.org</link>. 
            </p>
            <p>
                Jamie has one younger brother, Jeff, who is married to Gabriele and lives just outside of New York City. Coming from a small family,
                Jamie is excited to join Tim's huge extended family.
            </p>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
